# Shawn Price

604-839-2709 • Vancouver, Canada hi@shawnprice.com • shawnprice.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an entrepreneur, leader, coach, and manager who empowers individuals, teams, and organizations to ship products within an environment of support, safety, growth, and continuous learning.

Focussed on measuring and improving results, I bring 12 years of professional software engineering experience and understanding to the individuals and teams which I support.

As an Engineering Manager I bring more than three years of experience leading projects, individuals, and teams while effectively solving problems. With a bias towards action, I enable successful product delivery and individual growth through coaching and servant leadership.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

COMMIT Engineering Manager Vancouver November 2019 - Present

- Wore any hat requested of me as Commit continued to scale and execute early stage startup tactics
- Standardized the hiring process by defining and documenting the hiring funnel and creating a structured technical interview
- Laid the foundation for a healthy culture of diversity & inclusion, with an emphasis on mental health and women in tech
- Reporting to the CEO, created a Lean Canvas of a coaching system. Coaching will be a pillar of the unique Commit business model
- As Project Manager for a client engagement, replaced "no process" development with "light scrum" development. Under the former we were six weeks late delivering Phase 1. Under the latter the client had information needed to balance scope and schedule ensuring Phase 2 delivered on schedule delivering business value

CTO.ai Engineering Manager Vancouver January 2019 - July 2019

- Led multiple teams of software engineers of varying levels of experience to deliver quality code using quality methods within an inclusive and supportive environment
- Participated in hiring and grew team(s) headcount from seven to twenty direct reports
- Balanced monitoring and improving team processes while measurably improving results of software delivery
- Led a team creating a complex distributed ETL pipeline scale from 3 to 100 production data pipelines
- Collaborated with Product Managers and other stakeholders to balance deliverables, scope, and schedule
- During regular 1-1's with team members, grew skills and careers through mentorship, coaching, and sponsorship, while providing continuous feedback

Global Remote First (SF HQ) April 2018 - September 2018

- Worked and communicated effectively as part of a fully distributed team
- Developed Solidity smart contracts deployed to the Ethereum blockchain
- Created Distributed Web App (Dapp) using Javascript, Vue.js, Web3.js, and Truffle
- Developed ERC-721 token contract during beta through to Initial Coin Offering (ICO)
- Fully responsible for the creation of the web app mobile experience, ensuring compatibility with Coinbase Wallet and other wallet apps.

# CUMUL8 Technical Program Manager

Vancouver November 2017 - April 2018

- Mentored and coached team members via regular 1-1's, maintaining team member growth and happiness
- Introduced and managed the use of Jira Portfolio, bringing visibility to and confidence in our product roadmap to the team, management, and executive team
- Project managed the development of a big data visualization product ensuring team was operating
  efficiently and milestones were met with success
- Led, monitored, and improved team processes and culture

# REELHOUSE MEDIA Technical Program Manager

Vancouver March 2015 - November 2017

- Improved team focus and discipline by introducing the use of Objectives & Key Results (OKRs)
- Increased development output by championing and leading organizational agile transformation creating a greater than 40% improvement in development cycle time
- Managed multiple projects using light touch processes to capture accurate requirements, align stakeholders, and ensure rapid and successful product delivery
- Co-defined and co-executed product strategy and vision for Reelhouse and Slipstream products
- Increased organizational empathy by implementing "Everyone does support" culture change

## REELHOUSE MEDIA Software Engineer

Vancouver / Los Angeles March 2013 - November 2017

- As part of a development team of two, took the <u>Slipstream</u> product from concept to market in 3 months leaning heavily on React, Redux, GraphQL, Node.js, Koa, and MongoDB
- Lead the planning and implementation of a major refactoring of a video marketplace e-commerce system to accept multiple payment methods including Paypal, Stripe, and Bitcoin. This work led to an increase of sales due to greater accessibility for our global customer base
- Created and integrated a Video.js plugin for our 360 degree mobile video experience using WebGL,
   Javascript, HTML5, and CSS allowing our video platform to support VR filmmakers

## AFFINITY BRIDGE Agile Software Developer

Vancouver June 2008 - March 2013

- Worked closely with the Drupal open-source community to build and maintain community modules and share knowledge at community meetups and conferences
- Worked directly with more than 10 clients to build large scale custom CMS solutions that met customer business objectives
- Developed web applications using HTML5, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Drupal, and MySQL

### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

CO-ACTIVE TRAINING INSTITUTE Fundamentals Of Co-Active Coaching

UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA Award in Agile Leadership

BRITISH COLUMBIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Certificate Of Applied Web Development

### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

GitHub

https://github.com/sprice

NPM

https://www.npmjs.com/~sprice

Drupal

https://www.drupal.org/u/langworthy

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**SCRUM ALLIANCE** 

Certified Scrum Professional (CSP, expired March 2020. Renewal in progress)

**SCRUM ALLIANCE** 

Certified Scrum Master (CSM, expired March 2020. Renewal in progress)